Micheal Ighietsemhe

SENIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER | SENIOR NODE.JS DEVELOPER

michig3000@gmail.com michealdev.vercel.app github.com/micheal081 linkedin.com/in/micheal-ighietsemhe-502640222

SUMMARY

Experienced Senior Backend Developer skilled in Node.js and TypeScript. Transitioning to lead innovation and teams, driving 35% skills growth through 6 sponsor partnerships, and scaling APIs by 47%. Pioneered real-time product analytics, deployed OAuth security for 100% data protection, and led high-availability web app development for 354,600+ users.

EDUCATION & AWARDS

Olabisi Onabanjo University – Nigeria – Bachelor of Science (B.Sc) – Computer Science Awards: GoMyCode Hackathon – Second Place – Best Code (Gomycode.com) HiiT PLC – Outstanding Intern – First Place (Hiit.ng)

TECHNICAL/SOFT SKILLS

Node.JS • Nest.JS • TypeScript • JavaScript • React.JS • React Native • PostgreSQL • MySQL • Express.JS • Jira • Notion • Firebase • MongoDB • Azure • AWS • Prisma • Git • HTML • CSS • Clickup • Kubernetes • Docker • Husky • Kafka • Serverless • GitLab • Communication • Analytical & Problem Solving • Teamwork • Leadership • Drive & Initiative

WORK EXPERIENCE

Voja.Ai. – Backend Engineer – visit https://voja.ai

September 2023 - Present

- Developed a script to gather social media data (Instagram and TikTok) for over 1.7 million hotels. Scraped posts to validate hotels, enhancing UI interactivity and resulting in a 30% increase in stakeholder satisfaction.
- Integrated Auth0 services into the backend, automating the retrieval and updating of user details, reducing onboarding efforts by 27%.
- Implemented an autocomplete feature for user searches on hotels, cities, states, countries, and airports, leading to a 20% improvement in user satisfaction.
- Contributed to an endpoint utilizing OpenAI services to fetch detailed place descriptions, top places, and public transportation information based on user search queries.

Payflex Inc. – Senior Backend Engineer – visit https://payflexinc.com

June 2022 - August 2023

- Led four teams of 5 individuals in developing backend systems for providing financial services to 95% of the nation
- Connected team members with professional development and career opportunities offered by 6 prominent organization sponsors, resulting in 35% enhanced skill sets and accelerated career growth.
- Built and implemented RESTful APIs that facilitated seamless integrations with backend services enhancing scalability by 47%

Proddly LLC. - Backend Engineer

January 2020 - April 2023

- Led a team of 7 to develop a Price Viability Tool that provides real-time information on a product's retails using Node.JS and Express.JS, streamlining the daily workflow of merchant planners by 10%
- Developed and deployed OAuth authentication protocols for REST APIs, resulting in a 100% decrease in unauthorized data access incidents and a 30% boost in client satisfaction
- Designed and developed a scalable, high-availability web application handling 354,600+ concurrent users with minimal downtime.

Hifast.io. – Node.Js Developer Intern

June 2018 - November 2019

- Actively participate in agile development processes, ensuring sprint commitments are met with a 90% on-time delivery rate.
- Successfully implemented and optimized the 'Launch on Login' feature for web-app platforms, improving user engagement and increasing login rates by 25%.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Management Leadership for Tomorrow (MLT) – Career Prep Fellow

May 2022 - October 2023

• Choosen as one of 350 for an 18-month professional development program for high-achieving diverse talent